William Emmanuel Defty papers, 1868-1927
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Subgroup II: Business Records, 1886-1925
  - Series III: Mining reports, 1886-1925
    - Other States
      - New Mexico
        - Luna - Tres Hermanas - Zinc Property. 1903 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - South Carolina
        - York - Magnolia Mining Property. 1908 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Other Countries
      - Mexico/Sonora
        - Maps and Clippings. 1901/1903 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - San Pedro - Tucson and Gulf Railroad. 1902-1910 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - Altar - La Belen/Arizona-Mexican Copper Co. 1903-1904 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - Altar - La Calara/Arizona-Mexican Copper Co. 1901-1903 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - Altar - La Cananea Copper Co. 1903-1904 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Altar - El Carmen. 1903 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - Altar - Cerro Prieto Gold Mine. 1902 (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - Altar - El Congreso. 1902-1904 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - Altar - Colorado Iron Works Smelter (for Arizona-Arizona Mexican Copper Co.). 1904-1905 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - Altar - Gigante and Josefina/Coast Line. 1901-1902 (Box 7, Folder 10)
        - Altar - La Gran Proveedora/Arizona-Mexican. 1901-1905 (Box 7, Folder 11-14)
        - Altar - Juarez Mine. 1904-1906 (Box 7, Folder 15-17)
        - Altar - El Porvenir De Sonora/Coast Line. 1901-1902 (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
        - Altar - San Francisco Group. 1890/1899 (Box 7, Folder 20)
        - Altar - Sonora Milling and Mining. 1904-1906 (Box 7, Folder 21-23)
        - Altar - Tubatama Mining and Reduction. 1902 (Box 7, Folder 24)
        - Arizpe - Cerro Tordillo Copper Mines. 1905 (Box 7, Folder 25)
        - Arizpe - Cochise and Dewey Mines. 1903 (Box 7, Folder 26)
        - Arizpe - San Carlos. 1904 (Box 7, Folder 27)
        - Arizpe - San Felipe. 1901 (Box 7, Folder 28)
        - Cerro del Oro - La Seguama Mine. 1902 (Box 7, Folder 29)
        - Hermosillo - Barranca. 1906 (Box 7, Folder 30)
        - Hermosillo - Chipiona and Colorado Mine. 1901 (Box 7, Folder 31)
        - Hermosillo - Sonora Silver Mining Co. 1887 (Box 7, Folder 32)
        - Magdalena - Promontorio. 1901 (Box 7, Folder 33)
        - Moctezuma - Santa Fe Mines. 1901 (Box 7, Folder 34)
        - Ures - Las Coches Mining Property. 1907-1910 (Box 7, Folder 35)
        - Ures - El Oro Gold Properties. 1901-1903 (Box 7, Folder 36)
        - Zambona Development Co. 1906 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Mexico/Baja
        - Jan Juan y Los Flores - El Toro Mine/Gulf Copper. 1909 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Mexico/Michoacan
        - Henderson Property. 1902 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Mexico/Sinoloa
        - Regional Report. 1900? (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Jamaica
        - Cedar Hurst Property. 1914-1916 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Series IV: Other business reports, 1891-1923
    Contains maps and engineering reports relating to irrigation projects, along with records and correspondence regarding a ramie fiber company in which Mr. Defty's family was involved. This series also contains miscellaneous maps, drawings, receipts, and assay reports that could not be conclusively identified, and various mining equipment catalogs.
    - Arizona
      - Maricopa - Gila Irrigation/Valley Land & Canal/Arizona Construction Co. 1891-1893 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Maricopa - New York Canal and Irrigation Co. 1893-1894 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Pinal - Queen Creek Reservoir Co. 1912 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Yavapai - Pacific Water Power Co. 1909-1911 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - California
      - Antelope Valley Reservoirs, Dams and Irrigation. 1891 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Anglo-American and Anglo-Dutch Ramie Fibre and Paper Companies. 1895-1896 (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
      - Miscellaneous Business Records. 1899-1922 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Stock Certificates, Deeds, Agreements, Powers of Attorney. 1890-1906 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous Assay Reports. 1899-1906 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Mining Equipment Catalogs, Brochures. 1900-1920 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Series V: Maps and blueprints, 1886-1925
    Maps and blueprints are located in the map case in the northeast corner of the building. Materials associated with existing mining or other business reports are indicated as such with the box and folder number of the original report. For example, 3/4 Cochise - Wolframite Claims, 1900 indicates that the original mining report is found in Box 3, Folder 4. In addition, there are maps and blueprints not directly associated with existing reports. For example, Warren - Copper Mines, 1910 has no box and folder number preceding it, which means there is no original report. Numbers in parentheses following a mine or company name indicate the number of items for that mine or company in that box. The pound sign (#) indicates that for that mine or company, additional large maps or blueprints can be found in box 12.
    The bulk of the materials in boxes 9, 10 and 11 contain oversized maps and blueprints that are supplemental to the mining and other business report series. Box 11 also contains miscellaneous maps and mining equipment blueprints. Box 12 contains very large oversize material, including several hand colored items.
    - Mining Reports
      - Arizona
        - Cochise
          - Cochise -- Wolframite Claims (box 3 folder 4). 1900 (Box 9)
          - Tombstone -- Woolery Claims (box 3 folder 7). 1920 (Box 9)
          - Warren -- Copper Mines. 1910 (Box 9)
          - Warren -- Mining District. 1910 (Box 9)
        - Coconino
          - Grand Canyon -- United States Platinum Co. No Date (Box 9)
        - Gila
          - Globe -- Irene Group (box 3 folder 12). 1914-1925 (Box 9)
        - Maricopa
          - Camp Creek -- Parker Mines (box 3 folder 14). 1910 (Box 9)
          - Cave Creek -- Lone Star/Golden Reef (box 3, folder 17). 1922 (Box 9)
          - Magazine -- Cram Mountain Claims (box 3 folder 21). 1909 (Box 9)
          - Maricopa -- Independence Group/North Star (box 3 folder 24). 1911-1915 (Box 9)
          - Moor -- Hualapai Copper Co. (box 3 folder 26). 1908 (Box 9)
          - Ozborn -- Maricopa Copper Mines/Ozborn (box 3 folder 28). 1899 (Box 9)
          - Sunflower -- Sunflower Cinnabar (box 3 folders 32-33). 1914-1916 (Box 9)
          - Vulture -- Vulture Mine (box 3 folder 35). 1901-1916 (Box 9)
          - Winifred/Pinal -- North and South Groups (box 3 folder 38). No Date (Box 9)
        - Mojave
          - Maynard -- Wallapai & Victor Copper (box 3 folder 46). 1917-1920 (Box 9)
          - Peacock -- Hackberry Extension Mining (box 3 folder 47). 1918 (Box 9)
        - Pima
          - Greaterville -- Liberty Silver Mining Co. 1917 (Box 9)
        - Pinal
          - Superstition -- Young Mines (box 4 folder 17). 1923 (Box 9)
          - Sam Thorpe Claims. No Date (Box 9)
          - Woodbury Copper Co. 1917 (Box 9)
        - Santa Cruz
          - Harshaw -- Patagonia Chief Property (box 4 folder 19). 1907 (Box 9)
        - Yavapai
          - Agua Fria -- Little Daisy Group (box 4 folder 26). 1917 (Box 9)
          - Big Bug -- Little Jesse Group (box 4 folder 31). 1896-1901 (Box 9)
          - Black Canyon -- Gold Note Group (box 4 folder 33). 1904 (Box 9)
          - Black Rock -- Gunther Property (box 4 folder 40). 1899-1900 (Box 9)
          - Blue Tank -- Independence (box 4 folder 47). 1899-1903 (Box 9)
          - Blue Tank -- Big Tufa. No Date (Box 9)
          - Chaparral -- New Years Group (box 4 folder 51). 1916 (Box 9)
          - Eureka -- Lawler Group (box 5 folder 3). No Date (Box 9)
          - Eureka -- Seven Stars Gold Co. 1892 (Box 9)
          - Martinez -- United Gold Mines (box 5 folders 9-10). 1913-1915 (Box 10)
          - Santa Maria -- Central Group. 1908 (Box 10)
          - Verde -- Cleopatra Mining Co. (box 5 folder 20). 1911-1916 (Box 10)
          - Verde -- Pittsburg Jerome Property (box 5 folder 33). 1916 (Box 10)
          - Verde -- Verde Cobre Mining Co. (box 5 folder 38). 1916-1923 (Box 10)
          - Verde -- Washburn Group. 1916 (Box 10)
          - Verde -- Mining District. 1916 (Box 10)
          - Weaver -- Alvarado Gold Mine (box 5 folder 43). 1907 (Box 10)
          - Weaver -- Yarnell Property (box 5 folder 46). 1909 (Box 10)
        - Yuma
          - Ellsworth - Carmelita Mining Co. (box 5 folder 55). 1917-1919 (Box 10)
          - Plomosa -- Ibex Plomosa (box 6 folder 8). 1907 (Box 10)
          - Mohawk Mining Claims. 1900 (Box 10)
      - California
        - Riverside -- Stephens Property (box 6 folder 18). 1901 (Box 10)
        - San Bernadino -- Calico -- Mining District. 1889 (Box 10)
        - San Bernadino -- Daisy/Lily/Violet Quartz. No Date (Box 10)
        - San Bernadino -- Victoria Silver Mines. 1888 (Box 10)
        - Sovereign Cons Mines. No Date (Box 10)
      - Montana
        - Jefferson -- Colorado -- Angelica Mining Co. (box 6 folder 34). 1920 (Box 10)
      - Mexico/Sonora
        - Altar -- El Congreso Mining Certificate with revenu stamp (box 7 folder 8). 1902-1904 (Box 11)
        - Altar -- La Gran Porveedora/Arizona-Mexican Co. (box 7 folders 11-14). 1901-1905 (Box 11)
        - Altar -- Juarez Mine (box 7 folders 15-17). 1904-1906 (Box 11)
        - Arizpe -- Cerro Tordillo Copper Mines (box 7 folders 25). 1905 (Box 11)
        - Hermosillo -- Sonora Silver Mining Co. (box 7 folders 32). 1887 (Box 11)
        - Sonora Mining Districts. 1905 (Box 11)
    - Other Business Reports
      - Maricopa -- Gila Irrigation/Valley Land & Canal/Arizona Construction Co. (box 8 folder 1). 1891-1893 (Box 11)
      - Maricopa -- New York Canal & Irrigation Co. (box 8 folder 2). 1893-1894 (Box 11)
      - Yavapai -- Pacific Water Power Co. (box 8 folder 4). 1909-1911 (Box 11)
      - Anglo-American and Anglo Dutch Ramie Fibre & Paper Companies (box 8 folders 6-8). No Date (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Nevada -- Washoe County -- Reno & Sparks. No Date (Box 11)
      - Nevada -- California State Line -- Unprospected Area. No Date (Box 11)
      - Arizona -- The Mineral District Tributary to Prescott. No Date (Box 11)
      - Arizona & California & Mexico -- The Colorado Desert, Sonora, Mesa and Delta of the Rio Colorado. 1893 (Box 11)
      - Arizona. 1907 (Box 11)
      - Arizona & California -- Western Arizona/Southeastern California, Mining & Agricultural Districts. 1907 (Box 11)
      - Mining equipment blueprints. No Date (Box 11)
    - Mining Reports
      - Mexico/Sonora -- Altar --La Gran Proveedora/Arizona-Mexican (box 7 folders 11-14). 1901-1905 (Box 12)
      - Arizona/Yavapai -- Big Bug -- Little Jesse (folder 4 box 31). 1896-1901 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Arizona territory. 1903 (Box 12)
      - Blueprints for Nogales & Sonora Mfg Co. No Date (Box 12)
      - Fly wheel and coupling support. No Date (Box 12)
      - Smelting furnace/Henry Defty. 1888 (Box 12)
      - California -- Los Angeles -- Palmdale irrigation district. 1891 (Box 12)